Okay.
네
It's moment of truth time.
진실의 순간이에요
I have just taken our class tester.
방금 시험지를 먹었어요
You remember this class?
이 수업 기억나요?
Uh, it's the class that runs the evaluation across the full, uh, 250 data points from our test data
전체적인 평가를 수행하는 수업이에요 시험 데이터 세트에서 250개의 데이터 포인트를 통틀어서요
set.
약간 달라요
Uh, if you if you go through this, you'll notice there's some very subtle differences, because we're
여길 보시면 아주 미묘한 차이가 있는 걸 아실 겁니다 왜냐하면 우린 아이템 객체를
not taking an item object.
가져가지 않으니까요
We're taking a data set, a data point from our data set.
데이터셋에서 데이터 포인트를 가져오는 거죠
So there's a couple of small differences.
몇 가지 작은 차이가 있어요
But otherwise this tester is basically exactly the same, um, in terms of what it does.
하지만 그 외에는 이 테스터는 기본적으로 똑같아요
And it ends of course with this single line tester test.
물론 이 단선 테스터 테스트로 끝나죠
The model predict is the function that we just wrote that tries out our model against 250 points, and
모델 예측은 방금 작성한 함수로 250점 대 모델을 테스트해보고 테스트 데이터 세트에서
we pass in the test data set.
통과하는 거죠
And of course I've already run it and let me scroll through the results.
물론 이미 실행했죠 결과를 스크롤해 볼게요
So you get a sense it's right up at the there we go.
느낌으로 알 수 있죠 바로 위∙∙∙ get 됐네요
We'll take it to the top.
정상까지 올라갈 거예요
So you'll see there, of course, that first red item is where it predicted $1,800 for something that
보시다시피 첫 번째 빨간 항목은 374달러짜리 물건이 1,800달러로
costs 374.
예상됐어요
There's some more reds, there's some greens.
붉은색과 녹색도 있어요
Um, and it certainly gives you a sense that it's not like we're getting that.
우리가 그걸 못 느낀다는 걸 확실히 느낄 수 있죠
It's the model understands the task for this one.
이 모델은 이 작업을 이해하죠
For example, it guest $89.99.
예를 들어, 89달러를 게스트하죠 99살요
And the truth was 101 79.
진실은 101-79였어요
It's interesting that it's not sticking to the nearest whole dollar.
가장 가까운 금액이 아닌 게 흥미롭네요
It's it's still creating things with $0.99.
0달러로 뭔가를 만드는 거예요 99살요
Um, and you'll see that, uh, yeah, there's some there's some other problematic ones here, but there's
보시면 문제가 되는 색도 몇 개 있어요 녹색과
a greens and reds, greens and reds, but quite a few reds, quite a few reds.
붉은색이 있는데 붉은색이 꽤 많아요
So I will put us out of our misery and go straight to the charts.
이 고통을 끝내고 곧장 차트에 오를 거예요 Put it up Put it
Here it comes.
나오네요
Oh my goodness.
말도 안 돼요
It is a horrible, horrible result of 395.
395의 끔찍한 결과예요
In terms of the error, 395 uh, which you will remember, uh, is considerably worse than taking a
오차로 따지면 395%는 기억하시겠지만 무작위로 추측하는 것보다 훨씬 심각한
random guess.
수치죠
I think it's certainly worse than just taking the average number of the training data set.
훈련 데이터의 평균 수보다 확실히 더 나쁜 것 같아요
Not that it knew the training data set.
훈련 데이터는 몰랐지만요
Uh, and, uh, yeah, it's, uh, it's generally a horrible result.
네, 보통 끔찍한 결과죠
Um, Perhaps not massively surprising.
그렇게 놀랍진 않아요
It's a tiny model.
작은 모형이에요
It's been hugely quantized as well, and you can see visually what it's doing.
양자화도 잘 돼 있어서 눈으로 확인할 수 있어요
You can see that it has, um, had a few different levels that it's been most comfortable guessing at,
몇 가지 단계가 있는데 가장 쉽게 추측할 수 있는 단계죠 대부분 이 세 단계
and it's guessed most often at one of these three levels.
중 하나에서 추측해요
And unfortunately one of them is far too high.
안타깝게도 한 마리는 너무 높죠
We've never told the model not to go above $1,000.
모델에게 1,000달러 이상은 안 된다고 한 적이 없어요
It's not like that's a requirement.
꼭 그래야 하는 건 아니에요
It can guess whatever it wants, as could GPT four.
GPT 4처럼 원하는 건 뭐든 추측할 수 있죠
We've, uh um, not not given it that that, uh, that intelligence to to know that, um, and so it's
우리는 그걸 알 수 있는 지식을 주지 않았어요 그래서 너무 자주 너무
gone too high far too much of the time.
높이 올라갔죠
Uh, and it's really ruined the results.
그래서 결과가 엉망이 됐죠
So a poor performance from our base model.
기본 모델의 성능이 낮았어요
Not that surprising given the small number of parameters.
변수가 적은 걸 보면 그리 놀랍진 않네요
And of course, the challenge on our hands now is going to be, can we take this poor performing model
물론 이제 우리가 해결해야 할 과제는 성능이 떨어지는 모델을 미세
and use fine tuning, use a training data set to make it stronger?
튜닝과 훈련 데이터를 이용해 더 강하게 만드는 거죠
And can we get close to what a trillion parameter model can achieve.
그리고 1조 매개 변수 모델이 달성할 수 있는 것에 근접할 수 있을까요? Get it
So this is an 8 billion parameter model and it's been quantized.
80억 매개 변수 모델로 수량화되었어요
Can we get close to the the trillion plus model parameters in a major frontier model.
주요 개척 모델의 get 1조 이상의 모델 변수에 근접할 수 있을까요?
Because this is open source, it's free.
오픈 소스라서 무료예요
There's no API cost.
API 비용이 없어요
Wouldn't it be amazing if we could perform at that level, um, or at least beat a human?
그 수준으로 경기를 펼치거나 최소한 인간을 이기면 굉장하겠죠?
Right now the human beings are winning over an untrained llama.
훈련받지 않은 라마를 인간이 이기고 있어요
At least this human is one final thought to leave you with.
적어도 이 인간은 당신에게 마지막으로 남길 존재죠
You remember that this is quantized down to four bits.
이건 4분의 1로 퀀화되는 거 아시죠?
You might be asking yourself, how would it look if we quantized just to eight bits?
여러분은 궁금하실 거예요 우리가 8분의 1로 양자화되면 어떻게 보일까요?
If we kept the eight bit version and ran it through, it would be interesting to see whether the how
8비트 버전을 유지하고 실행하면 성능이 얼마나 영향을 미치는지 알 수
much the performance was impacting by going all the way down to the double quantized four bit.
있을 거예요 이중 퀀타이즈 된 4비트 버전까지 살펴보면요
And indeed you can do that, of course.
물론 그럴 수 있죠
And this framework gives us a lovely way to to in a very simple, tangible way.
이 프레임워크가 아주 간단하고 실재하는 방법을 제공하죠
See the difference.
차이를 보세요
So remember 395 is how far this is wrong.
395까지 세면 얼마나 잘못된 건지 아시겠죠
So in this other tab I have just run it with the only quantized to two eight bits.
다른 탭에서 유일한 8비트로 퀀타이즈 된 걸 실행했어요
So if I go up to the top, you can see that I've got up here four bits set to false and otherwise it's
위로 가면 4bit가 false로 설정된 게 보이시죠? 아니면 완전히
exactly the same.
똑같아요
Notebook.
공책이에요
Let's scroll all the way down and go straight to the results.
스크롤을 쭉 내려서 결과를 보죠
It looks like it's in here.
여기 있는 것 같아요
Hold on.
잠깐만요
Build the tension.
긴장감을 조성해요
And here we go.
자, 보세요
So it's also pretty horrible performance.
그러니 연기도 형편없죠
But it is better 395 became 301.
395가 301이 된 게 더 낫죠
And that's not surprising at all.
놀랄 일도 아니죠
You know it's got a twice the amount of information.
정보가 두 배나 많거든요
Um so you know again quantizing did have an impact on accuracy, but perhaps we would have expected
다시 말씀드리지만 퀀타이즈는 정확도에 영향을 미쳤습니다 하지만 8비트 모델은
the eight bit model to have done even better.
더 잘했을지도 모르겠네요
So so it wasn't there wasn't such a great difference between them.
그래서 두 사람 사이에 큰 차이는 없었어요
Uh, but it does show you, of course, that the bigger model is able to do a better job.
물론 더 큰 모델이 더 잘한다는 걸 보여주죠
All right.
좋아요
With that, that's been pretty interesting.
그게 참 흥미로웠어요
Pretty revealing.
노출이 심하네요
Let's go back to the slides to wrap up and summarize.
슬라이드로 돌아가서 마무리하고 요약해보죠